Guide to the Byzantine and Roman Catholic Church Memorial Booklets Collection, 1949-1978 AIS.1979.42
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Byzantine and Roman Catholic Church Memorial Booklets Collection
1949-1978
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Catholic Church
AIS.1979.42
2 microfilm_reels (776 frames)
This collection contain 21 memorial booklets from a variety of Byzantine and Roman Catholic Churches, 1949-1978. The booklets commemorate a variety of church events including dedications, rededications, anniversaries, building fund drives, and consecrations.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection contains memorial booklets from a variety of Byzantine and Roman Catholic Churches located in Southwestern Pa., Northeastern Ohio, and one church in Annandale, Va. The booklets commemorate a variety of church events including dedications, rededications, anniversaries, building fund drives, and consecrations. The collection is made up of two series. Series I contains 17 booklets from Byzantine Catholic Churches and Series II contains 4 booklets from Roman Catholic Churches.
The Southwestern Pa. communities included are: Avella, Canonsburg (Washington County); Ambridge (Beaver County); Clymer (Indiana County); Greensburg, Harrison City, Jeanette, Monessen (Westmoreland County); McAdoo (Schuykill County); McKeesport (Allegheny County); New Salem, Uniontown (Fayette County); Nicktown (Cambria County); and Trauger (Westmoreland County). Those in Ohio are in Youngstown and Newton Falls.
Note: The first part of this collection (394 frames) is filmed on the second half of a reel containing the St. Peter's Evangelical Lutheran Church, Uniontown Pa. Records, AIS.1980.22. The second part of this collection (382 frames) is filmed at the beginning of a reel which also contains the Trinity Lutheran Church, Wexford, Pa. Records, AIS.1980.31.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collected was microfilmed with permission by Archives of Industrial Society using funds provided by the NEH grant RC-0036-79-1210, "Survey and Acquisition of Source Materials Relating to Immigrant and Ethnic Life in Southwestern Pa." in 1979.
Existence and Location of Orginals
Original records are in the possession of Robert J. Skovira.
Previous Citation
Byzantine and Roman Catholic Church Memorial Booklets Collection, 1949-1978, AIS.1979.42, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Memorial Booklets, Byzantine and Roman Catholic Churches, Southwestern Pa.; Northeastern Ohio; and Annandale, Va., 1949-1978, AIS Micro 79:42, Archives of Industrial Society, University of Pittsburgh
Church buildings -- Virginia -- Annandale; Church buildings -- Ohio; Church buildings -- Pennsylvania; Churches and Synagogues; Annandale (Va.) -- Church history; Ohio -- Church history; Pennsylvania -- Church history; Catholic Church -- Ohio
- Byzantine Catholic Church Booklets, I.
  - Silver Jubilee, 1924-1949, Byzantine Slavonic Rite, Catholic Diocese of Pittsburgh (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 1)
  - Building Fund, St. Mary's, Monessen, PA., 1957 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 1)
  - Dedication, St. John's, Pittsburgh, PA., 1959 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 1)
  - Dedication, St. Mary's, Monessen, PA., 1960 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 1)
  - Rededication, St. Mary's, Trauger, PA., 1961 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 1)
  - Dedication, Educational and Recreational Center, St. Mary's, Trauger, PA., 1961 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 1)
  - Dedication, St. Mary's, Youngstown, OH., 1961 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 1)
  - Dedication, St. John the Baptist, Avella, PA., 1962 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 1)
  - 50th Anniversary, St. Micheal's, Canonsburg, PA., 1962 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 1)
  - Dedication, St. Mary's, Ambridge, PA., 1963 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 1)
  - Dedication, Motherhouse and Novitiate, Mt. St. Macrina, Uniontown, PA., 1964 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 1)
  - Dedication, St. Mary's Assumption, New Salem, PA., 1967 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 1)
  - 50th Anniversary, St. Michael's, Newton Falls, OH., 1972 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 2)
  - Dedication, Epiphany of Our Lord, Annadale, VA., 1973 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 2)
  - Dedication, St. Anne's, Clymer, PA., 1974 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 2)
  - 75th Jubilee, St. Nicholas', McKeesport, PA., 1976 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 2)
  - Rededication, St. Michael's, McAdoo, PA., 1978 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 2)
- Roman Catholic Church Booklets, II.
  - Dedication, Ascension Church, Jeanette, PA., 1961 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 2)
  - Dedication, St. Barbara, Harrison City, PA., 1963 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 2)
  - Consecration, Blessed Sacrament Cathedral, Greensburg, PA., 1973 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 2)
  - History, St. Nicholas', Nicktown, PA., 1977 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 2)